Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Electronic Files, 1982-2003; Series IX; 5.1 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - Computer disks (3.5 inches)
    - Women in Photography A-H, 1997; 9 computer disks
      - WIPBB sept 1997 Nov 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0205; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPC sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0206; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPD sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0207; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPE sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0208; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPF sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0209; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPG sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0210; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPH sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0211; 1 (Box 232)
    - Women in Photography A-K, 1998; 4 computer disks
      - WIPA Jan 1998 June 1998 August 1998, 2003-wa-0811-b-0212; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPB Jan 1998 June 1998 August 1998, 2003-wa-0811-b-0213; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPBB Jan 1998 June 1998 August 1998, 2003-wa-0811-b-0214; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPC WIPD WIPE WIPF WIPG WIPH WIPI WIPJ WIPK August 1998, 2003-wa-0811-b-0215; 1 (Box 232)
    - Women in Photography A-Z, 1998-1999; 17 computer disks
      - WIPA 10 March 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0216; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPB 10 March 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0217; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPBB 10 March 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0218; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPBBB 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0219; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPC June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 Sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0220; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPD June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 Sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0221; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPE June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0222; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPF June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0223; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPG June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 1 May 99 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0224; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPH June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0225; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPI,J,K June 1998 1 November 1998 1 February 1999 May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0226; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPL + M February 1999 May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0227; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPN WIPO/WIPP/WIPO February 1999 May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0228; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIPR May 1999 1 Sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0229; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIP S may 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0230; 1 (Box 232)
      - WIP T,U,V, May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0231; 1 (Box 232)
      - Wip W,X,Y,Z May 1999 1 sept 99 1 Nov 99, 2003-wa-0811-b-0232; 1 (Box 232)
    - Women in Photography A-Z, 1999-2000; 8 computer disks (Box 233)
      - WIPAA.DOC 18 Dec 1999 5 Jan 2000 15 ApriL 2000, 2003-wa-0811-b-0233; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPB.Doc WIPBB.Doc WIPBBB.Doc Dec 1999 15 ApriL 2000, 2003-wa-0811-b-0234; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPC.Doc WIPD.Doc WiPE.Doc December 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0235; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPF.Doc WIPG.Doc WiPH.Doc December 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0236; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPI.Doc WIPJ.Doc WIPK.Doc WIPL.Doc December 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0237; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPM.Doc WIPN.Doc WIPO.Doc WIPP.Doc December 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0238; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPQ.Doc WIPR.Doc Wips.Doc Wipt.doc December 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0239; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPU.Doc WIPV.Doc WIPW.Doc WIPX.Doc WIPY.Doc WIPZ.Doc Dec 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0240; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography A-K, 2001 September; 9 computer disks (Box 233)
      - WIPA 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0241; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP B 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0242; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP BB 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0243; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP BBB 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0244; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPC 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0245; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP D 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0246; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP F-G 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0247; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP H 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0248; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIP I-J-K 10 sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0249; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography A-B, 2001; 2 computer disks (Box 233)
      - WomenA.Doc WomenB1.Doc 28 sept WomenB2.Doc 2001 15 oct, 2003-wa-0811-b-0250; 1 (Box 233)
      - Women B., 2003-wa-0811-b-0251; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Ascii.WS, 1997 April (Box 233)
      - Women Photographers 5/97 ascii.ws, 2003-wa-0811-b-0252; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Biographies, 1996 February (Box 233)
      - Wipbio.wps 2 Feb 96, 2003-wa-0811-b-0253; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Book, 1997 April (Box 233)
      - 5/97 Women Photographers the book preface.txt intro.wps portolio.wps wpi#1.txt + wps wip#2.txt + wps biblio.wps [now Microsoft Word 2.0], 2003-wa-0811-b-0254; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Humboldt, 1998-1999; 3 computer disks (Box 233)
      - 1-14-98 HUMWIP.DOC [a-z list] HUMWIP2.DOC [chronological] HWIPTODO.DOC['To Do' List], 2003-wa-0811-b-0255; 1 (Box 233)
      - A_B.DOC Q_S.DOC C_D.DOC T_Z.DOC E_F.DOC G_H.DOC I_K.DOC L_M.DOC N_P.DOC >>HUMBOLDT BIO'S>>, 2003-wa-0811-b-0256; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPA.Doc Hum.Women Bios Dec 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0257; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Humboldt Co. Camera Club, 1999 December (Box 233)
      - WIPFCC FCC.Doc Humb. Co. Camera Clubs Dec 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0258; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Inventory, 1996-2000; 4 computer disks (Box 233)
      - Wipinv2 1 February 1996 15 sept. 1996 1 ApriL 1997 1 July 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0259; 1 (Box 233)
      - Wipinv2 25 sept 1997, 2003-wa-0811-b-0260; 1 (Box 233)
      - WIPINV2 Oct 15, 1999, 2003-wa-0811-b-0261; 1 (Box 233)
      - Wipinv2 7 Nov 2000, 2003-wa-0811-b-0262; 1 (Box 233)
    - Women in Photography - Nebraska, circa 2000 (Box 233)
      - Women Photographers in Nebraska Access 2000 Word doc also, 2003-wa-0811-b-0263; 1 (Box 233)
    - Unlabeled disks, undated; 14 computer disks (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0811-b-0264; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0012; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0013; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0014; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0015; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0016; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0017; 1 (Box 233)
      - "Cewbooks", 2003-wa-0204-h-0018; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0019; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0020; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0204-h-0021; 1 (Box 233)
      - port.doc, 2003-wa-0204-h-0022; 1 (Box 233)
      - bios.doc, 2003-wa-0204-h-0023; 1 (Box 233)
      - [no label information], 2003-wa-0811-b-0265; 1 (Box 233)
  - Magnetic Tapes
    Magnetic tape cartridges for a Hewlett Packard Colorado Travan Tape Drive.
    - Backups, 2001 July-September, undated; 2 magnetic tapes
      - 1, 2003-wa-0811-b-0266 (Box 233)
      - 2 6 July 2001 10 Aug 2001 19 Sept 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0267; 1 (Box 233)
  - Compact Disks
    - Peter Palmquist at the International Center of Photography, 1977 March
      - 27 PETER PALMQUIST AT ICP 4/17/77 35:53, 2003-wa-0811-b-0268; 1 (Box 234)
    - Amon Carter Museum, "Carleton Watkins: Photographer of the American West" and "Wet-Plate Photography Process", 1983
      - AV 26 Amon Caeter Museum Carleton Watkins: The Wet Plate Photography Process, 2003-wa-0811-b-0269; 1 (Box 234)
    - Peter Palmquist, "Stereoscopic Immortality," keynote speech at the National Stereoscopic Association Convention, San Diego, California, 1993
      - #23 STEREOSCOPIC IMMOR 1 CUT 18:34, 2003-wa-0811-b-0270; 1 (Box 234)
    - Peter Palmquist, "Etched by Light: The Daguerreotype and Social Exposure," Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1999 November 7
      - #25 ETCHED BY LIGHT 60 MIN, 2003-wa-0811-b-0271; 1 (Box 234)
    - Mary Ellen Mark, lecture at Photo L.A., Santa Monica, California, 2000 January 23
      - #24 Mary Ellen Mark 1/2 PHOTO LA 2000 46:44, 2003-wa-0811-b-0272; 1 (Box 234)
      - #24 Mary Ellen Mark 2/2 PHOTO LA 46:58, 2003-wa-0811-b-0273; 1 (Box 234)
    - Peter Palmquist, talk at the Annual Historical Society Luncheon Meeting of the Humboldt County Historical Society, 2001 February 4
      - AV 19 Peter Palmquist: entire tape, talk to HCHS Luncheon 2001 Feb. 4th RT:1:13:15, 2003-wa-0811-b-0274; 1 (Box 234)
    - Salmon River Restoration Coucil, History CD Project, 2001
      - Salmon River Restoration Council History CD Project 2001, 2003-wa-0811-b-0275; 1 (Box 234)
    - Peter Palmquist, CBS, undated
      - CBS Dub Master. AV 21 FX, 2003-wa-0811-b-0277; 1 (Box 234)
    - AV 20 Keet - TV Living Biographies Peter Palmquist: Photo Historian/Photographer RT: 29 minutes, 2003-wa-0811-b-0276; 1 (Box 234)
- Additions from Other Collections, Series X
  - Correspondence
    - California Historical Society (Box 235)
    - Canda, Elio E. (Box 235)
    - Classic Camera Show and Trade Fair (Box 235)
    - George Eastman House (Box 235)
    - International Photography Hall of Fame (Box 235)
    - Osman, Colin (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter, Outgoing correspondence to reviewers of his history of the stereograph in California (Box 235)
    - Regional Photographic History Group (Box 235)
    - Southern California Camera and Photo Show (Box 235)
  - Publications and Publicity
    - Taplin, Glen W. "Timber Carnival," American Forests (1962 June): 34-35. Illustrations probably by Palmquist (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "The Photographers of Siskiyou Caounty, CA., 1850-1920," self-published, 1978 January (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Watkins – The Photographer as Publisher." California History: The Magazine of the California Historical Society 57, no. 3 (1978): 252-265. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Carleton E. Watkins: A Checklist of Surviving Photographically Illustrated Books and Albums." The Photographic Collector 2, no. 1 (1981) 4-12. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Carleton Watkin's Oldest Surviving Landscape Photograph." History of Photography: An International Quarterly 5, no. 3 (1981): 223-224. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Taber Reprints of Watkins Mammoth Plates." The Photographic Collector 3, no. 2 (1982): 13-20. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Carleton E. Watkins at Work." History of Photography: An International Quarterly 6, no. 4 (1982): 291-326. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Watkins' 'New Series' Stereographs." The Photographic Collector 3, no. 4 (1982-1983): 11-20. Palmquist, Peter E. "Watkins' 'New Series' Stereographs, Part II." The Photographic Collector 4, no. 1 (1983): 28-39. Palmquist, Peter E. "Watkins' 'New Series' Stereographs, Part III." The Photographic Collector 4, no. 2 (1983): 18-27. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter. "Views to Order." Portfolio 5, no. 2 (1983): 84-90 (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Carleton Watkins: Master of the Grand View" The Rangefinde r 32, no. 6 (1983): 6-8, 30-34. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. The First Ten Years: A Listing of My Photographic History Obsession, 1973-1983 (Arcata, California: P. E. Palmquist, 1983). (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Photographic Archaeology: A Case for Regional Research." In Second Western Photohistory Symposium (Riverside, California: California Museum of Photography, 1984), 17-29. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Behind the Scenes: A Potpourri of Western Photographic Studios and Darhrooms, 1850-1950." The Photographist 66 (1985): 10-25. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Resume of Photographic History, 1973-1986." (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter. "Silver Plates Among the Goldfields: The Photographers of Siskiyou County, 1850-1906." California History 65, no. 2 (1986): 114-125. (Box 235)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Discovering Yosemite." Timeline 14, no. 3 (1997): 40-54. (Box 235)
    - Woolley, John. Funeral service for Peter Eric Palmquist (Box 235)
  - General Research Files
    - Biographical Files
      - Longpré, Paul de (Box 235)
      - Snelling, Henry Hunt (Box 235)
      - Biographical Files for Male Photographers, 66 (Box 236)
        Biographical files formerly in the Peter Palmquist Collection of Women in Photography (WA MSS S-2600) for male photographers.
      - Biographical Files for Male Photographers Not in the American West, 60 (Box 237)
        Biographical files formerly in the Peter E. Palmquist Collection of Male Photographers in the American West for male photographers located outside the region.
    - Carleton Watkins Research
      - Carleton Watkins material at the Getty Research Institute, notes (Box 238)
      - Copy photographs (Box 238)
      - Photocopies of photographs (Box 238)
    - California
      - Notes on photographers in the Daily Alta California newspaper (Box 239)
      - Pence, Ellsworth D., "French Place Names in California"
    - California Engravings
      - Barber & Baker (Box 239)
      - Gleason's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, 1851-1855 (Box 239)
      - Harper's Weekly, 1879 (Box 239)
      - Howe, Henry. Historical Collections of the Great West (Cincinnati: H. Howe, 1851) (Box 239)
      - Illustrated London News, 1851-1853 (Box 239)
      - Kilburn (Box 239)
      - Worcester & Co. (Box 239)
      - Unidentified publisher, Residence of Dr. [Alemby] Jump, Downieville, Sierra Co., Cal. (Box 239)
    - Canadian Photographers, 17 (Box 239)
      - Birrell, Andrew. "Survey Photography in British Columbia, 1858-1900", 1981-1982 (Box 239)
      - Brown, Patty. "Montreal Photographers, 1840-1950", circa 2002 (Box 239)
      - Burant, J. "Photographers and Photographic Studio, St. John, New Brunswick, 1845-65", 1973 (Box 239)
      - Carey, Brian. "Daguerreotype in the National Archives of Canada", 1988 (Box 239)
      - Carey, Brian, "An Imperial Gift", 1986 (Box 239)
      - Garrett, Graham, "Canadian Daguerrians", undated (Box 239)
      - Harper, J. Russell. "Daguerreotypists and Portrait Takers in Saint John", 1955 (Box 239)
      - Koltun, Lilly. "Pre-Confederation Photography in Toronto", 1978 (Box 239)
      - Mattison, David. "Camera Workers, 1901-29: Checklist", 1986 (Box 239)
      - Mattison, David. "Bibliography" from Camera Workers, 1985 (Box 239)
      - Mattison, David. "Early British Columbia Photographers, 1858-1900: A Preliminary Checklist", 1981 (Box 239)
      - Mattison, David. "Shadows of History: A Selected, Annotated Bibliography of the History of Canadian Photography", 1993 (Box 239)
      - Mautz, Carl, "British Columbia" (Box 239)
      - Schwartz, Joan. "The Past in Focus: Photography and British Columbia, 1858-1914" (Box 239)
      - Schwartz, Joan. "The Photographic Record of Pre-Confederation British Columbia", 1977-1978 (Box 239)
      - Silversides, Brock. "Calgary Photographers, 1883-1950", 1992 (Box 239)
    - Cased Photographs
      - Copy photographs of cased photographs (Box 239)
      - Craig's Daguerrian Registry Newsletter (Box 239)
      - Daguerrian Society (Box 239)
    - Humboldt County
      - McKay, Tom. Humboldt County floods, 1909-1915, notes (Box 240)
      - Palmquist, Peter E. Humboldt County photographers, male and female (Box 240)
      - Palmquist, Peter E. "Miscellaneous Writings in California Photographic History, Volume 1, Humboldt County" (Box 240)
    - Humboldt State University
      - Natural Resources Photography, broadside for a class taught by Peter E. Palmquist, 1974? Fall (Box 240)
      - Tanner, William R. Humboldt State University history, 1986 (Box 240)
    - Places Named after Photographers
      - Engloffstein, F. W. von (Box 240)
      - Meany, Edmund S. (Box 240)
    - Reuel Colt Gridley and the Sanitary Sack of Flour
      - Reuel Colt Gridley, 4 (Box 240)
      - National Sanitary Cake (Box 240)
    - Spirit Photography
      - Mumler, William H. (Box 240)
      - Straiton, Thomas Bell (Box 240)
    - Stereographs
      - Stereographs by unidentified Japanese photographers (Box 240)
      - Underwood & Underwood ephemera (Box 240)
      - Yosemite Valley, copy photographs of stereographs (Box 241)
  - Material for Publications and Exhibitions
    - Capturing Light: Masterpieces of California Photography, 1850-2000, Artist biographies, circa 2001 (Box 242)
    - The Pam Mendelsohn Collection of Instructive Books for Women 1790-1950, Illustrations, circa 1994 (Box 242)
    - Women in Photography International Archive, 1997 (Box 242)
  - Collection Inventories
    - Copy photographs of children (Box 242)
    - "A Name Listing og Nineteenth Century California Photographers Located in the Files of Peter E. Palmquist" (Box 242)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., Notes related to publications in his collections (Box 242)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., Photocopies of "favorite" photographs in his collections (Box 242)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., Notes related to cased photographs (Box 242)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., Notes on photographs by Western male photographers (Box 242)
    - "Symbols to primary bibliographic sources" (Box 242)
  - Business Records
    - Business cards, invoices, and labels (Box 242)
    - Business licenses (Box 242)
  - Oversize Material
    - Palmquist, Peter, E. Sketch for an unidentified publication, undated (Box 243 (Oversize))
    - Collected Material
      - Color inkjet print of a sketch by an unidentified artist of gold mining in California, circa 1849-1852 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Copy photograph of a daguerreotype by an unidentified photographer of Portsmouth Square, San Francisco, California, circa March-May 1850 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Copy photograph of a daguerreotype by an unidentified photographer of the gravesite of Phillip A. Potter, July 1852? (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Times Press (Eureka, California), Reproduction of The Daily Citizen (Vicksburg, Mississippi) newspaper, July 2, 1863, circa 1890 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Plats for land in Shasta County, California, 1870 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - "The Pigimies in Piccadilly: Lucia Zarate and General Mite, with the Exhibitor," The Illustrated London News, 1880 November 27 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Orpheum Theatre (San Francisco), Broadside for performances, including many by Sarah Bernhardt, 1913 February 16-21 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Motion Picture and General Investment Co. (Hong Kong) Film still from Hua lo shui liu hong [ Tragedy of Love ], 1966 (Box 243 (Oversize))
      - Copy photographs of Arthur T. Gill, "Recognition of Photographic Processes," History of Photography, 2, No. 1 (1978): 34-36 (Box 243 (Oversize))
- Printed Material
  Books, periodicals, and other printed material collected by Palmquist.
  - Printed Material (Box A)
  - Printed Material (Box B)
  - Printed Material (Box C)
  - Printed Material (Box D)
  - Printed Material (Box E)
  - Printed Material (Box F)
  - Printed Material (Box G)
  - Printed Material (Box H)
  - Printed Material (Box I)
  - Printed Material (Box J)
  - Printed Material (Box K)
  - Printed Material (Box L)
  - Printed Material (Box M)
  - Printed Material (Box N)
  - Printed Material (Box O)
  - Printed Material (Box P)
  - Printed Material (Box Q)
  - Printed Material (Box R)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box S (Broadside oversize))